Contact

513.872.9243

zoe.teets@gmail.com

Nashville, TN

www.github.com/zoeteets

m www.linkedin.com/in/zoe-teets

About Me

Analytical and creative problem solver with a keen eye for design. After 10 years as a performer and creator of Children's Theatre, I pivoted to the financial industry in 2020 and found immense joy in analyzing data to improve business processes. Passionate about investigating, creating, and communicating solutions that directly contribute to company growth and brand image.

Skills

SQL

Microsoft Excel

Tableau

PowerBI

Python

Jupyter

Pandas, Numpy

Agile Workflow

Kanban Boards

Github

Education

Nashville Software School

Data Analytics Bootcamp

West Virginia University

Bachelor of Multidisciplinary Studies

Zoe Teets

Data Analyst

Projects

- **Fifth Third Bank Central Operations** (Excel) Analyzed Fifth Third Bank's order fulfillment process. Established new workflow that reduced required labor by 2 hours daily, created a new SOP to efficiently identify and isolate high-risk clients, reducing weekly risk of errors by 9%.
- Nashville City Cemetery (Excel) Cleaned and analyzed data to find compelling data points, used Canva to create original marketing materials.
- App Trader (SQL) Analyzed Apple and Google Play store data combined with company profit model to recommend apps with the highest return on investment.
- Lahman Baseball (SQL) Analyzed baseball statistics over 20 tables to find correlations and abnormalities.
- Early Intervention System (Python) In partnership with the Department of Developmental Disabilities, analyzed the referral database to address company concerns regarding success rate and recommend areas of improvement.

Work Experience

Nashville Software School

Data Analytics Apprentice

May 2022 - August 2022

Intensive full-time bootcamp focusing on data analytics fundamentals and problem solving. Used real-world datasets and included projects where findings were presented to stakeholders from the community.

- Analyzed data using Microsoft Excel, including utilizing pivot tables and lookups, and connected to external data sources using the PowerPivot add-on.
- Built and deployed dashboards using Tableau and PowerBI
- Retrieved and analyzed data using PostgreSQL
- Source code version control with Git/GitHub
- Project management/tracking with GitHub project boards and issue tracking
- Wrangled data and performed exploratory data analysis using Python's pandas library
- Created data visualizations using matplotlib and seaborn
- Gathered data through APIs and webscraping
- Performed geospatial analysis using geopandas and folium

Fifth Third Bank

Personal Banker I

August 2021 - May 2022

- Contributed average of 51% of total branch checking accounts, 36% of total branch savings accounts over three quarters.
- Established new relationships with local businesses and consistently exceeded customer call expectations.

Fifth Third Bank

Vault Teller

February 2020 - August 2021

- Managed cash flow, daily financial reports, and shipments to/from the Federal Reserve for the Fifth Third Cash Vault
- Established new workflow process, new Standard Operating Procedure (SOP), and wrote technical manuals to assist training.
- Escalated innovative efficiency idea resulting in Fifth Third investing \$500,000 in new automation equipment.

VIPkid

English Tutor, virtual

2018-2020

Walgreens Pharmacy

Pharmacy Technician / Shift Lead 2011-2018